To me, there are three main threats
which are going to jeopardize personal
training over the next few years.
And this video is about preparing for them
so
that you can survive this oncoming wave.
The first one has to be weight loss
medications.
And even calling them weight loss
medications, I don't think is enough here.
We have a GLP-1. We can look at Ozempic,
known as Wegovy at the top.
Then a better one came along known as
Mounjaro, which is tirzepatide.
Now,
you could call Ozempic a single agonist,
Mounjaro a double
agonist. Then retatrutide
is on its way through trials as a triple
agonist.
GLP, GIP,
and the effect it's going to have,
potentially treating
fatty liver disease, obesity.
Andrew Huberman reckons it could be a
trillion-dollar
drug.
The effects of these weight loss
medications are already impacting the
economy in ways that we can see. Aviation.
Planes are using less fuel than they did a
few years ago.
In jewelry, jewelers
are now using less gold in wedding rings.
Obesity rates,
for the first time in history,
have started to decline.
The world is changing because of these
drugs.
Whether you like that or not,
it doesn't matter.
That's the reality of it.
Now,
there is opportunity within this because
there's now a massive cohort of
people that would never have stepped foot
in a gym, that wouldn't care about
coaching, that now
are mindful of muscle wastage,
getting adequate protein,
and preserving muscle tissue.
Those people will find their way into the
fitness
industry.
So whilst weight loss medications could
extinct us, they can also bring
us opportunity. But then again,
that opportunity is only going to be
available
to those that are out there doing the
things that modern businesses need to do
to
get attention.
Standing by reception in the gym
is not going to get
you all of those people on weight loss
medications.
You're going to have to be at the
forefront of social media.
Could make this a whole video altogether.
But that's the first threat.